Chitrang Patel

Sr. Android Developer

https://chitrang200889.github.io/vcard/

E-mail: chitrang200889@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-8511928411

Skype: chitrang200889

StackOverflow: /chitrang

I am a mobile application developer with around four years of Android Application development experience. Over the years, I have worked on challenging projects which keeps boosting me to learn, explore, implement new and challenging things. I've played roles in almost every aspects of the software development, like communicate with users, technical teams, and management to collect requirements, describe software product features and technical designs, project documentation. Worked on Android apps which includes:

- Android Frameworks/Technologies Activity life cycle, Fragments, Services, Broadcast Receiver, AppCompat and Support libraries, Material Design
- Design Pattern MVP
- Reactive Extensions RxAndroid
- Dependency Injection Dagger2
- · Networking Retrofit, OkHttp3, Volley
- Client-Server REST, HTTP Web Services, WCF
- Data Parsing JSON, XML, SOAP
- Data Storage SQLite, Content Providers, Shared Preferences, External Storage
- Background Processing and Multithreading Service, AsyncTask
- Image downloading Glide, Picasso
- UI development Native UI controls, Custom UI Controls, Animation
- Multimedia Camera, Gallery, Audio, Video
- Video TextureView with native MediaPlayer, ExoPlayer, Vitamio, grafika
- Social Network Integration Facebook, Twitter, google plus
- Payment Gateway PayPal, WePay
- Third Party API Shopify, Google, Firebase
- Third Party libraries Credit-Card Scan, barcode scanner
- Analytics tools Google analytics, Firebase
- Ads AdMob
- Chat ejabberd, openfire
- Location Maps, Network Provider, GPS, Fused Location Provider
- Push-Notification GCM, FCM
- In-app purchase In-app Billing API
- Version Control systems GitHub, Bitbucket, GitLab, SVN
- Testing Espresso

Work Experience:

- ➤ Worked at **BosLeo**, Valsad as **Tech Lead** since November 2016 till October 2017.
- ➤ Worked at **Dynamic Dreamz**, Surat as **Team Lead in Mobile App Development** from September 2015 to October 2016.
- > Worked at Krtya Softwares, Surat as Mobile App Developer from June 2013 to August 2015.

Education:				
Degree	Board	Specialization	Year	Grade
➤ M.E.	IISc, Bangalore	Comp. Sci.	2012	5.0/8.0
▶ B.E.	Gujarat University	Info. Tech.	2010	59.02%
➤ H.S.C.	G.S.H.E.B.	Science	2006	75.20%
➤ S.S.C.	G.S.H.E.B.	Science	2004	83.29%

Projects:

eAudit	
Description	- Provides fast, flexible and dynamic audit and inspection platform.
	- Designed for global workforce communities operating across multiple industry sectors.
Technology	Android, php, MySQL
Role	Involved in code review, refactoring, improve, new features development, documentation
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.eAuditTech.release
	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.eaudittech.eauditlite

SodaScan	
Description	 Select your soda or soft drinks from listing of well categorized listing- Add to cart your products Apply coupons on your total amount Any easy payment option with paypal or credit card. With existing order history a convenient way to reorder them
Technology	Android, REST API, OpenCart
Role	Involved in Development
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.cinch.sodascan

Notification Block	ver .
	- Enable and Disable notification of individual/all applications
	- Support android system apps like Email, Gmail, Messaging
	- Support downloaded apps like social apps like Facebook, Twitter, Messenger, Line, Wechat,
Description	etc.
	- Monitor applications notifications counts by sorting alphabetically, descending counts and
	ascending counts.
	- Clear counts to monitor counts as per your time duration.
Technology	Android
Role	Involved in Design, Development
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.invenit.notificationblocker

Qooter	
	- Compare Rates Instantly from 100+ Top Rated Insurance carriers
	- Term Life Insurance Quotes
Description	- Final Expense Insurance Quotes, Senior Life Insurance Quotes
Description	- Medicare Supplement Quotes
	- Health Insurance Quotes and enrollment
	- Retirement Planning Quote
Technology	Android, REST API, PHP, MySQL
Role	Involved in Development, Team Lead
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.instant.quoter

All Share and Shop		
	- All-in-one Social Media android app	
	- Secure and protective app lock	
Description	- Flawless chatting with friends	
	- 100% secure social media platform	
	- Quick and smooth shopping experience	
Technology	Android	
Role	Involved in Design, Development	
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dynamicdreamz.myvault	

FlashPoll	
	- FlashPoll is an independent app to gather public opinion on matters of interest to the people.
Description	- Send you surveys on topics of interest to you directly to your mobile.
	- Allows you to select the topics of interest to you, and will also be distributed via Social Media
	and traditional media channels.
Technology	Android, REST API, Yii, MySQL
Role	Involved in Design, Development
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.flashpoll

TCITG	
Description	 Go to guild for anything and everything available on the Turks and Caicos Islands Categorize Restaurants, Things to do and Place to stay on each Island Contact Vendors to make inquiries or book reservations directly With our help Deck you can contact us directly with any questions you may have Watch Videos
Technology	Android, REST API, Yii, MySQL
Role	Involved in Design, Development, Team Lead
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.tcitg

Spot it	
Description	- Location checkin and Sharing with friends APP
	- Group chats with your contacts so you can easily stay in touch with your friends or family.
	- Share your visited spots with groups.
	- Spotit List – Keep memory of your places that you have already visited!
Technology	Android, REST API, Yii, MySQL
Role	Involved in Team Lead
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dynamicdreamz.spotit

Fiducadia	
	- Provides a question bank for students, which when answered gives them marks and/ or
Description	model answers
	- Above is linked to their parents and teachers
Technology	Android, REST API, Yii, MySQL
Role	Involved in Team Lead
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fiducadia
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fiducadia

Kids Education w	ith Fun
	- Identify the picture and write the spelling
Description	- Read the words and select the correct picture
Description	- Join the upper case and lowercase letter.
	- Remember and make a pair of Words and object name.
Technology	Android
Role	Involved in Team Lead
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dynamicdreamz.educationwithfun

Time Converter	
	- Highly flexible time conversion
Description	- Accurate Time Display
Description	- Supports World Clock Time Zone
	- Favorite list for preferred Time Zone
Technology	Android
Role	Involved in Team Lead
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dynamicdreamz.timeconverter

MyBusTransport	
Description	- MyBusTransport Mobile Application of MyiSchool is basically designed to make it easy for
	the parents to know the whereabouts of the bus.
	- Parents will be notified about the expected/ arrival time of the bus at their route point.
	- Parents will get to know the details of the driver as well.
Technology	Android, ASP.NET, MS SQL
Role	Involved in Design, Development,
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.krtya.mybustransport

MyBackOffice	
Description	- MyBackOffice is single-login Business Backoffice System and is specially designed by Krtya
	Software for easy implementation of back office actions by the executives of the organization. - Every record is disclosed in the system which allows the managers to be aware of the
	current scenario of the company.
Technology	Android, ASP.NET, MS SQL
Role	Involved in Design, Development,
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.krtya.mybackoffice

Givr	
Description	 Designed to help you manage your giving, our desire is to help keep giving simple. Make one time or recurring gifts Add multiple credit or debit cards Track your giving over time Manage or update recurring transactions Automatic email receipts for every gift
Technology	Android, ASP.NET, MS SQL
Role	Involved in Development,
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.givr.android

AJS mobOPAC & AMA mobOPAC	
Description	- Facilitates patrons of the library to access details about the various resource holdings of the
	AJS & AMA Library
Technology	Android, SOAP, ASP.NET, MS SQL
Role	Involved in Development,
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.webopac
	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.amamobopac

CauseClassifieds	
Description	- App for donating Charity by purchasing products and make payments similar as amzon,
	tradus etc.
Technology	Android, ASP.NET, MS SQL
Role	Involved in Development,
Link	-

Identacor	
Description	 - Mobile app to work with the Identacor's cloud-based identity management service, which provides SSO for Web applications. - Also gives users a single interface through which they can tab between all of the SaaS applications they're entitled to use.
Technology	Android, SOAP, ASP.NET, MS SQL
Role	Involved in Development,
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.startsso.identacor

SimplyOPT	
Description	- Mobile App of SimplyOPT for students or professional to find internship, job based on their
	VISA in the U.S. job market.
Technology	Android, PhoneGap, jQuery Mobile, HTML5 , ASP.NET, MS SQL
Role	Involved in Development,
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.krtya.simplyopt

eBarcode	
Description	- eBarcode is a simple yet powerful bar-code scanner for android phone. It allows you to scan
	these tags you now see almost everywhere
Technology	Android, Zxing library for barcode scan , ASP.NET, MS SQL
Role	Involved in Development,
Link	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ebarcode.andoid